KEVIN S. CHOI

Cell: 408-621-5580 Email: kevin@kchoi.co Personal Site: kchoi.co

SUMMARY

Well-rounded IT Engineer with 10+ years of experience in the IT industry. Specializing in infrastructure build outs, server & network configurations, administration, and executive level documentation. Looking to expand my skills in site reliability, automation, and security.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, Validation Number W6Y2NVJCBEV11JK3 Cisco Meraki Networking Associate Palo Alto Networks Accredited Sales Expert Datto Advanced Sales Tactics

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Full-Stack:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Git

Operating Systems:

Windows

NT/95/98/XP/Vista/7/10/2003/2008R2/2012R2/2016/Nano *Linux*

Ubuntu/Xubuntu/Mint/FreeNAS/RedHat/RedHat OpenShift Container Platform

Networking Stack:

Cisco, Meraki, SonicaWALL, Fortigate, Checkpoint, Palo Alto Networks

Cloud Services:

AWS Serverless Computing Stack, Heroku, Digital Ocean, Softlayer, Docker, Microservices

Applications & Platforms:

VMWare ESX/ESXi, Microsoft Hyper-V, TrueNAS SAN and NAS, Box, Dropbox, Zendesk, ServiceNow, ZOHO, Salesforce, JAMF Casper Suite, Cylance, Cisco ISE, Splunk, Sumologic, AppDynamics, DynaTrace, Centrify, Okta, Kaseya, Atera, N-Able, Solarwinds Orion, Zabbix, Nagios, FOG, Infoblox, Citrix XenApp, SeeBurger, BMC Control-M

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

First Republic Bank, San Francisco, California Senior Site Reliability Engineer

Aug 2018 – Jan 2019

- Responsible for proactive monitoring, maintaining, troubleshooting, repairing and upgrading of servers, network
 infrastructure, software services, power distribution and environmental systems for internal network as well as
 monitoring of connectivity to vendors, partners and subsidiaries.
- Monitor microservices on AWS environment and collaborate with other departments and vendors on troubleshooting urgent, upgrade, and ongoing issues.
- Implement PowerShell scripts that reduce manual tasks to compare the completion of virtual image template reports.
- Respond to Cisco Identity Service Engine alerts by troubleshooting unauthorize devices in the production and non-production network.
- Build Windows Servers and RedHat virtual instances through multiple clusters in ESXi 6.5.
- Coordinate with Information Security Network Engineers to assign proper VLAN and subnets for newly built virtual servers to be placed in proper security groups in both production and non-production environments.
- Identify and coordinate with other departments to resolve issues related to virtual and physical technical issues located in the primary, secondary, and disaster recovery data centers.
- Provide joint technical experiences to troubleshoot individual branch outages that is related to system or network high availability infrastructure.
- Maintain and manage Windows ADM accounts to allow administrators access to appropriate platforms.
- Responsible for developing, configuring, monitoring, troubleshooting and maintaining complex enterprise-wide file transfers and coordinating with internal and external contacts.
- Participate in disaster recovery and business continuity tests by performing recovery procedures and troubleshooting issues that may be encountered.
- Monitor and manage of automated tasks such as system backups and scheduled tasks.

Halcyon Financial Technology, San Francisco, California

Apr 2016 - Aug 2018

Senior Information Services Advisor

- Architected, project managed, implemented, and maintained small-to-medium sized environments delivering IT solutions utilizing a hybrid or full cloud architecture.
- Automated virtual instances with VMware by creating workstation and server templates.
- Implemented self-healing rules on Windows workstations and servers with Solarwind Nable.
- Monitored and managed intrusion prevention system and intrusion detection system (IPS/IDS) using Cisco Meraki Advance Security platform, Sumologic, and Splunk.
- Implemented remote monitoring and management platforms that include Kaseya, Atera, Logmein, and Solarwinds Nable
- Attended annual IT meetings with Managing Partners, Chief Financial Officers, and Chief Security Officers to discuss high level projects (Azure Enterprise Mobility Suite, Box, Palo Alto Networks) and security implementation (BCP, DR, Data Breach).
- Performed cyber security audits to meet company requirements, SEC regulations, and FINRA regulations.
- Discovered vulnerabilities and performed remediation using Nessus, vulnerability scans, and Cylance, penetration testing.
- Managed and revised business continuity procedures and disaster recovery documentations for business-critical systems at multiple financial firms.
- Performed and provided executive reports on annual Datto disaster recovery testing by project managing and implementing Datto SIRIS 3 backup.
- Designed and implemented multi-site full stack Cisco Meraki networks. Architected the network with high availability, scalability, and provided robust features.
- Troubleshooted network related incidents across LANs, WANs, MPLs, and VPNs.
- Managed ordering of IT equipment, acquisition of IT equipment, inventory, tracking, and disposition of hardware and software.

FixSwift, San Francisco, California

Dec 2013 - Apr 2016

Director of IT & Operations

- Doubled company revenue from 2014 to 2015 by initiating new product lines.
- Managed Dell R730 ESXi Hosts using high availability techniques to keep uptime and customer satisfaction as top priority.
- Maintained and configured iXsystems TrueNAS Z20 SAN that acted as an iSCSI for multiple virtual servers/desktops and appliance servers (Ruckus, Unifi, Zabbix, FOG, Fortinet).
- Administered Windows Server support on IBM Softlayer virtual/baremetal servers to financial institutions and terminal service app clients.
- Constructed GPO and Batch scripts to automate Workstation and Server setups.
- Provided technical guidance, professional development, and career progression to 12 employees.

Cisco Systems Inc., San Jose, California

Sept 2010 - Oct 2012

System Administrator, Department of Service Bureau Solutions

- Responsible for system security on 60+ department servers (Cisco UCS Server, Cisco MCS-7800, HP Proliant Server, HP Storageworks SAN).
- Analyzed Nagios alerts for vital threats on both LAN & Dark networks (Cisco UCS 6140XP & Catalyst 3560G).
- Operationalized mass communication plans for monthly updates & restarts for MS Server 2003/R2 & 2008/R2.
- Administered SQL backups and maintenance plans to recover data without the extending downtime.
- Project managed future build outs for Hyper-V productions, SAP Business Object, and Oracle Database compatibility with current SQL servers.

Covexxan, San Jose, California

Jun 2005 - Aug 2008

Information Technology Support Specialist

- Designed and implemented internal layouts of all touch screen desktops to accommodate hardware peripherals.
- Implemented fingerprint readers (internal and external devices) in various components and application framework for each product.

EDUCATION

B.A. Economics - San Jose State University - San Jose, California **Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp** - UC Berkeley Extension - San Francisco, California